In this video, I'd like to
このビデオでは
tell you a bit about the
大きなマージンによる分類の
math behind large margin classification.
背後にある数学について、ちょっと話しておきたい。
This video is optional, so please feel free to skip it.
このビデオはオプショナルです。だからどうぞご自由にスキップしちゃって下さい。
It may also give you better
このビデオでは、また、
intuition about how the
サポートベクターマシンの
optimization problem of the
最適化問題が、どのように
support vex machine, how that
大きなマージン分類器を導くのかについての
leads to large margin classifiers.
より良い直感も与えたいと思う。
In order to get started, let
始めるにあたって
me first remind you of a
まずベクトルの内積について
couple of properties of what vector inner products look like.
幾つかの性質を思い出しておこう。
Let's say I have two vectors
2つのベクトル、uとvが
U and V, that look like this.
あったとする。こんな感じの。
So both two dimensional vectors.
つまりどちらも二次元ベクトルだ。
Then let's see what U
そしてu転置のvが
transpose V looks like.
どんな風になるか見てみよう。
And U transpose V is
u転置 v はまた、
also called the inner products
ベクトルuとvとの
between the vectors U and V.
内積、とも言われる。
Use a two dimensional vector, so
二次元のベクトルを使う事で
I can on plot it on this figure.
この図にプロットする事が出来る。
So let's say
さて、これが
that's the vector U. And
ベクトルuとしよう。
what I mean by that is
これの意味する所は、
if on the horizontal axis that
水平軸上で、
value takes whatever value
何かしらの値u1を取り、
U1 is and on the
そして垂直軸上では
vertical axis the height
その高さは
of that is whatever U2
何かしらの値u2を取る、
is the second component
これがベクトルuの
of the vector U. Now, one
第二成分である、という事。
quantity that will be nice
ここで、得ておくと良い
to have is the norm
一つの量として、
of the vector U. So, these
ベクトルuのノルムがある。
are, you know, double bars on
これらの、左と右の両方にある
the left and right that denotes
二重線が、
the norm or length of
uのノルム、言い換えると長さを表す。
U. So this just means; really the
つまりこれは単に、
euclidean length of the
ベクトルuのユークリッド距離を表すに過ぎない。
vector U. And this
そして、
is Pythagoras theorem is just
ピタゴラスの定理により、
equal to U1
イコール u1の二乗に
squared plus U2
足すことの u2の二乗、
squared square root, right?
これをルートを取る。
And this is the length of the vector U. That's a real number.
そしてこれはベクトルuの長さで、それは実数だ。
Just say you know, what is the length
この長さ、
of this, what is the
ここのこのベクトルの
length of this vector down here.
長さ。
What is the length of this
ここに今書いた矢印の長さ、
arrow that I just drew, is the normal view?
これがuのノルムだ。
Now let's go back and
さてここで、戻って、ベクトルvを見てみよう、
look at the vector V because we want to compute the inner product.
何故なら内積を計算したいのだから。
So V will be some other
さて、vもまた何らかの
vector with, you know,
別のベクトルで、
some value V1, V2.
何らかの値、v1とv2がある。
And so, the vector
だからベクトルvも
V will look like that, towards V like so.
こんな感じに、vベクトル。
Now let's go back
ここで、戻って、
and look at how to compute
uとvの内積を計算する方法を
the inner product between U
見てみよう。
and V. Here's how you can do it.
それはこんなやり方で出来る。
Let me take the vector V and
ベクトルvに対して
project it down onto the
それをベクトルu上に射影しよう。
vector U. So I'm going
つまり、直角に
to take a orthogonal projection or
射影する、
a 90 degree projection, and project
あるいは90度に射影する、そしてそれを
it down onto U like so.
u上に下ろす。
And what I'm going to do
そしてやるべき事は、
measure length of this
この赤い線、たった今引いたこれの
red line that I just drew here.
長さを測る。
So, I'm going to call the length of
この赤い線の長さを
that red line P. So, P
pと呼ぶ事にしよう。
is the length or is
するとpはベクトルvを
the magnitude of the projection
ベクトルuに射影した時の
of the vector V onto the
長さ、大きさである。
vector U. Let me just write that down.
ここに書き記しておこう。
So, P is the length
つまりpは
of the projection of the
ベクトルvを
vector V onto the
ベクトルuに射影した時の
vector U. And it is
長さである。
possible to show that unit
そして内積である u転置 vは
product U transpose V, that
p掛ける uのノルム、あるいは長さに
this is going to be equal
等しくなる、
to P  times the
という事を
norm or the length of
示す事が
the vector U. So, this
出来る。
is one way to compute the inner product.
つまり、これは内積を計算する一つの方法である。
And if you actually do
そして実際に幾何学を用いると
the geometry figure out what
pが何なのか、uのノルムが何なのかを
P is and figure out what the norm of U is.
知る事が出来る。
This should give you the same
この結果は
way, the same answer as
内積の別の計算方法と
the other way of computing unit product.
同じ答えとなるべきだ。
Right.
でしょ？
Which is if you take U
それは uの転置 vで、
transpose V then U transposes
u転置 は
this U1 U2, its a
u1, u2。
one by two matrix, 1
これは1x2 行列。それに
times V. And so
かけることのv。
this should actually give you
つまり、これは実際に
U1, V1 plus U2, V2.
u1 v1 足す事の u2 v2 を与える。
And so the theorem of
つまり、線形代数の定理として
linear algebra that these two
これら二つの式は
formulas give you the same answer.
同じ答えとなる。
And by the way, U transpose
ところで、uの転置 vは、
V is also equal to
v転置 uとも
V transpose U. So if
等しい。
you were to do the same process
だから同様のプロセスを反対に行えば、
in reverse, instead of projecting
vをuに射影する代わりに
V onto U, you could project
uをvに射影出来て、
U onto V. Then, you know, do
同様のプロセスだが
the same process, but with the rows of U and V reversed.
uとvの役割を反転させると、
And you would actually, you should
実際にも同じ数字を得る、
actually get the same number whatever that number is.
その数字がなんであれ。
And just to clarify what's
この等式で何が起こっているのかを
going on in this equation the
もう少し明らかにしておく。
norm of U is a real
uのノルムは実数で
number and P is also a real number.
pもまた実数だ。
And so U transpose V is
だから u転置 v は、
the regular multiplication as two real numbers of
単なる二つの実数の、普通の掛け算で、
the length of P times the normal view.
pの長さ 掛ける uのノルム。
Just one last detail, which is
最後に一つ細かい話を。
if you look at the norm of
pのノルムを見る時には、
P, P is actually signed so to the right.
pは実際は符合つきだ。
And it can either be positive or negative.
それはプラスにもマイナスにもなりうる。
So let me say what I mean
ようするに、
by that, if U
ベクトルuが
is a vector that looks like
このようなベクトルだとして、
this and V is a vector that looks like this.
vがこんなベクトルだとすると、
So if the angle between U
つまりuとvのなす角が
and V is greater than ninety degrees.
90度より大きければ、
Then if I project V onto
vをu上に射影すると、
U, what I get
得られる射影は
is a projection it looks like
こんな感じとなり、
this and so that length
これがpの長さとなる。
P. And in this
そしてこの場合、
case, I will still have
u転置 vは
that U transpose V is
基本的には、依然として
equal to P times the
p掛ける uのノルム、となるが、
norm of U. Except in
しかしこの場合は、
this example P will be negative.
pが負になる所だけが違う。
So, you know, in inner products if the angle
つまり、内積においては、
between U and V is less
uとvのなす角が
than ninety degrees, then P
90度未満の時は、
is the positive length for that red line
pは赤い線の正の長さとなり、
whereas if the angle of this
一方でここの角度が
angle of here is greater
90度以上の時は、
than 90 degrees then P
ここのpは
here will be negative of
マイナスの長さ、
the length of the super line of that little line segment right over there.
マイナスの、ここの線分の長さとなる。
So the inner product between two
つまり、二つのベクトルの内積は
vectors can also be negative
マイナスになる事がある、
if the angle between them is greater than 90 degrees.
もしなす角が90度より大きければ。
So that's how vector inner
以上がベクトルの内積が
products work. We're going to
どう機能するかだ。
use these properties of vector
これらのベクトルの内積の
inner product to try
性質を用いて、
to understand the support
ここのサポートベクターマシンの
vector machine optimization objective over there. Here
最適化の目的関数を理解しよう。
is the optimization objective for the
これが以前に見た、サポートベクターマシンの
support vector machine that we worked out earlier. Just for
最適化の目的関数だ。
the purpose of this slide I
このスライドの目的の為に
am going to make one simplification or
一つ単純化しておこう、
once just to make the objective easy
つまり、目的関数を分析しやすくする為に
to analyze and what I'm going to do is
切片項を
ignore the indeceptrums. So, we'll just ignore theta 0 and set that to be equal to 0. To
無視する事にする。 つまりシータ0を無視する、つまりイコール0とする。
make things easier to plot, I'm also going to set N the number of features to be equal to 2. So, we have only 2 features,
またプロットしやすいように、n、つまりフィーチャーの数を2とする。
X1 and X2.
つまり、x1とx2だけとする。
Now, let's look at the objective function.
ここで、目的関数を見てみよう。
The optimization objective of the
SVMの目的関数を。
SVM. What we have only two features.
フィーチャーは二つだけなので、
When N is equal to 2.
何故ならn=2だから、
This can be written,
これは以下のように書ける：
one half of
1/2の
theta one squared plus theta two squared.
シータ1の二乗 足すことの シータ2の二乗、と。
Because we only have two parameters, theta one and thetaa two.
何故なら我らは、二つのパラメータだけ、シータ1とシータ2だけしか持たないから。
What I'm going to do is rewrite this a bit.
そしてこれをちょっと書き換える。
I'm going to write this as one
これを、1/2の
half of theta one
シータ1の二乗に
squared plus theta two squared and
足す事の シータ2の二乗、
the square root squared.
そしてこれらのルートを取る。
And the reason I can do that,
こんな事が出来る理由というのは、
is because for any number, you know, W, right, the
任意の数wに対して、
square roots of W and
wを二乗して、
then squared, that's just equal
それ全体のルートを取ると、それはちょうどwと等しくなるから。
to W. So square roots
つまり、ルートして二乗は
and squared should give you the same thing.
同じ物を返す。
What you may notice is that
ここで気づく事として、
this term inside is that's
この中の項は、
equal to the norm
シータのノルムと
or the length of the
言い換えるとベクトルシータの長さと
vector theta and what
等しい。
I mean by that is that
そしてそれによって意味する事は、
if we write out the
ベクトルシータをこんな風に
vector theta like this, as
書き下すと、
you know theta one, theta two.
つまり、シータ1, シータ2,と書くと、
Then this term that I've just
するとこの今赤で下線を引いた
underlined in red, that's exactly
この項は、これは正確に
the length, or the norm, of the vector theta.
ベクトルシータの長さ、ノルムである。
We are calling the definition
前のスライドにあった、
of the norm of the vector that we have on the previous line.
ベクトルのノルムの定義に等しい。
And in fact this is actually
そして実際に、これは
equal to the length of the
ベクトルシータの長さに
vector theta, whether you write
等しい。たとえあなたが
it as theta zero, theta 1, theta 2.
シータ0, シータ1, シータ2で書いても、
That is, if theta zero is equal to zero, as I assume here.
ここで仮定したようにシータ0が0だから、
Or just the length of theta
または単にこれはシータ1, シータ2の長さでもあるが、
1, theta 2; but for
このスライドではシータ0を
this line I am going to ignore theta 0.
無視するのだったから、
So let me just, you know, treat theta
シータをこんな風に
as this, let me just
シータの、このシータ1, シータ2のノルムを
write theta, the normal
こんな風に
theta as this theta 1,
書いてみよう。
theta 2 only, but the
だが、この数学は
math works out either way,
どっちでも成立する。
whether we include theta zero here or not.
シータ0を含めようとも、無視しようとも。
So it's not going to matter for the rest of our derivation.
だからこれは以下の導出には、影響しない。
And so finally this means
そして最終的に、これは
that my optimization objective is equal
私の最適化の目的関数が
to one half of the
1/2のシータのノルムの二乗に
norm of theta squared.
等しい事を意味する。
So all the support vector machine
つまりサポートベクターマシンがやる事の全ては、
is doing in the optimization
最適化の目的関数として、
objective is it's minimizing the
パラメータベクトルのシータの
squared norm of the square
ノルムの二乗、つまり長さの二乗を
length of the parameter vector theta.
最小化しようと試みる。
Now what I'd like to do
ここで私はこれらの項を見て、
is look at these terms, theta
シータ転置 xを見て、
transpose X and understand better what they're doing.
それらが何をやっているのかをもっと良く理解していこう。
So given the parameter vector theta and given
さて、パラメータベクトルのシータが与えられたとして、
and example x, what is this is equal to?
手本のxが与えられたとすると、これは何に等しいだろうか？
And on the previous slide, we
前のスライドでは、
figured out what U transpose
u転置 v とはどんな物なのかを見ていった、
V looks like, with different
uとvは別のベクトル。
vectors U and V. And so we're
そこで我らはそれらの定義を
going to take those definitions, you know, with theta
持ってきて、シータとx(i)に
and X(i) playing the
uとvの役割を
roles of U and V.
させてみよう。
And let's see what that picture looks like.
するとどんな絵となるかを見てみよう。
So, let's say I plot. Let's say I look at
さて、プロットし、、、さて、たった一つの
just a single training example. Let's say I
トレーニング手本を見てみるとする。
have a positive example the drawing
陽性の手本が一つあるとして、
was across there and let's say that is
その場所に十字を描いておくとする。
my example X(i), what
これを手本x(i)としよう。
that really means is
それが実際に意味する事は、
plotted on the horizontal axis
横軸にある値、x(i) 1、
some value X(i) 1
そして縦軸に
and on the vertical axis
ある値x(i) 2を
X(i) 2.
プロットした、という事。
That's how I plot my training examples.
これがトレーニング手本のプロットの仕方だった。
And although we haven't been really
そして、ここまでの所、
thinking of this as a vector, what
これが実際にはベクトルであるとは考えてこなかったが、
this really is, this is a
これは本当は
vector from the origin
原点、0, 0から
from 0, 0 out to
このトレーニング手本の位置までの
the location of this training example.
ベクトルだ。
And now let's say we have
そして今、パラメータベクトルが
a parameter vector and
あるとして、
I'm going to plot
それも同様にベクトルとして
that as vector, as well.
プロットする。
What I mean by that is if I plot theta 1
どういう事かというと、シータ1をここに、
here and theta 2 there
シータ2をここにプロットすると、
so what is the inner
内積である シータ転置 x(i) は
product theta transpose X(i).
どうなるだろうか？
While using our earlier method,
以前の手法を用いると、
the way we compute that is we
それを計算する方法は、
take my example and
手本に対して、
project it onto my parameter vector theta.
それをパラメータベクトルのシータの上に射影する。
And then I'm going to look
そして次にこの線分の
at the length of this segment
長さを見る、
that I'm coloring in, in red.
今赤で描いているこの長さだ。
And I'm going to
そしてこれを、
call that P superscript I
p上付き添字iと呼ぼう、
to denote that this is a
これはi番目のトレーニング手本の
projection of the i-th training example
パラメータベクトル、シータに対する
onto the parameter vector theta.
射影を表す。
And so what we have is
すると我らが得るのは、
that theta transpose X(i) is
シータ転置 x(i) は
equal to following what
前のスライドにあった、
we have on the previous slide, this
以下に等しい。
is going to be equal to
これは p掛ける
P times the
ベクトルシータのノルム、長さに
length of the norm of the vector theta.
等しくなる。
And this is of course also equal to
そしてこれはもちろん、
theta 1 x1
シータ1 x1 足すことの シータ2 x2
plus theta 2 x2. So each
に等しくなる。
of these is, you know, an equally
つまりこれらはそれぞれどれも、
valid way of computing the
シータとx(i)の内積を計算する
inner product between theta and X(i).
同じように正統な方法である。
Okay.
オーケー。
So where does this leave us?
すると何だろう？
What this means is that, this
これの意味する所は、
constrains that theta transpose X(i)
この制約条件、シータ転置 x(i) が
be greater than or equal to one or less than minus one.
1以上か-1以下という条件、
What this means is that it
この意味する所は、
can replace the use of constraints
制約に使われている式を
that P(i) times X
p(i) 掛ける x が1以上、
be greater than or equal to one.
に置き換える事が出来る。
Because theta transpose X(i) is
何故なら シータ転置 x(i) は
equal to P(i) times the norm of theta.
p(i)掛けることの シータのノルムに等しいから。
So writing that into our optimization objective.
つまり、以上を最適化の目的関数に書きこむと、
This is what we get
これが得られる、
where I have, instead of
ここでは
theta transpose X(i), I now
シータ転置 x(i)の代わりに、
have this P(i) times the norm of theta.
今度は p(i)掛けるシータのノルム となっている。
And just to remind you we
そして、思い出そう、
worked out earlier too that
前に見てみたように、
this optimization objective can be
この最適化の目的関数は、
written as one half times
1/2掛けるシータのノルムの二乗、
the norm of theta squared.
とも書けるのだった。
So, now let's consider
では下にあるような
the training example that we
トレーニング手本を
have at the bottom and
考えてみよう、
for now, continuing to use the simplification that
そしてここでも、シータ0が0と等しいという
theta 0 is equal to 0.
単純化を継続する。
Let's see what decision boundary the support vector machine will choose.
サポートベクターマシンがどんな決定境界を選ぶかを見てみよう。
Here's one option, let's say
ここにそんな選択肢の一つがある。
the support vector machine were to
サポートベクターマシンが仮に
choose this decision boundary.
この決定境界を選んだ、と仮定してみよう。
This is not a very good choice because it has very small margins.
これはとても良い選択という訳では無さそうだ。何故ならマージンがとても小さいから。
This decision boundary comes very close to the training examples.
この決定境界はトレーニング手本のとても近くを通ってる。
Let's see why the support vector machine will not do this.
何故サポートベクターマシンがこれを行わないかを見ていこう。
For this choice of parameters
このパラメータの選択において、
it's possible to show that the
パラメータベクトルは実際に
parameter vector theta is actually
決定境界と90度の角度をなす事が
at 90 degrees to the decision boundary.
証明出来る。
And so, that green decision boundary
つまり、この緑の決定境界は
corresponds to a parameter vector
この方向を向いたパラメートルベクトルのシータに
theta that points in that direction.
対応している。
And by the way, the simplification that
ところで、シータ0がイコール0だという
theta 0 equals 0 that
単純化は、単に
just means that the decision boundary
決定境界が原点、ここの(0, 0)を
must pass through the origin, (0,0) over there.
通らないといけない、という事を意味しているに過ぎない。
So now, let's
ではここで、
look at what this implies
これが最適化の目的関数に対して
for the optimization objective.
何を意味しているかを見ていこう。
Let's say that this example here.
この手本がここにあったとする。
Let's say that's my first example, you know,
これが私の最初の手本、
X1.
x(1)だとしよう。
If we look at the projection
この手本のパラメータシータに対する
of this example onto my parameters theta.
射影を見てみると、
That's the projection.
これが射影となる。
And so that little red line segment.
つまりこの赤い線分。
That is equal to P1.
これはイコールp1だ。
And that is going to be pretty small, right.
そしてこれは極めて小さい。でしょ？
And similarly, if this
そして同様に、このここの手本を見ると、
example here, if this happens
これをx2とすると、
to be X2, that's my second example.
これが二番目の手本という事だが、
Then, if I look at the projection of this this example onto theta.
この手本のシータに対する射影を見てみよう。
You know.
お分かりの通り、
Then, let me draw this one in magenta.
これをマゼンタで描く事にすると、
This little magenta line segment, that's
この小さなマゼンタの線分、
going to be P2. That's
これがp(2)となる。
the projection of the second example
これが二番目の手本を
onto my, onto the direction
パラメータベクトルシータに
of my parameter vector theta which goes like this.
射影した物で、それはこんな感じになる。
And so, this little
つまり、この小さな射影の
projection line segment is getting pretty small.
線分は、極めて小さくなってしまう。
P2 will actually be a negative number, right so P2 is
p(2)は実際には負の数だから、p(2)は
in the opposite direction.
反対の向きになる。
This vector has greater
このベクトルは
than 90 degree angle with my
パラメータベクトルから90度より
parameter vector theta, it's going to be less than 0.
大きな角度となるので、0以下となる。
And so what we're finding is that
すると分かる事は、
these terms P(i) are
これらの項、p(i)は
going to be pretty small numbers.
極めて小さな数となるという事だ。
So if we look at
つまり最適化の目的関数を見ると、
the optimization objective and see, well, for positive examples
陽性の手本に対しては
we need P(i) times
p(i)掛ける シータのノルムが
the norm of theta to be bigger than either one.
1以上である必要があるが、
But if P(i) over
ここのp(i)、
here, if P1 over here
ここのp(1)が
is pretty small, that means
とても小さければ、
that we need the norm of
シータのノルムは
theta to be pretty large, right? If
とても大きくならないといけない。でしょ？
P1 of theta is small
p(1) が小さくて、
and we want P1 you
p(1)掛けるシータのノルムを
know times in all of theta
1以上に
to be bigger than either one, well
したいのだから、
the only way for that
この条件を真にする
to be true for the profit that
唯一の方法は、
these two numbers to be large
この二つの数が大きくなるには、
if P1 is small, as we
p(1)が小さいとするなら、
said we want the norm of theta to be large.
シータのノルムが大きくなる必要がある。
And similarly for our
同様に陰性の手本に対しては、
negative example, we need P2
p(2) 掛けることの
times the norm of
シータのノルムが、
theta to be
-1未満で
less than or equal to minus one.
なくてはならない。
And we saw in this
そしてこの手本に対しては
example already that P2
p(2)は極めて小さい
is going pretty small negative number,
負の数である事を既に見た。
and so the only way for
だからその条件が満たされる
that to happen as well is
唯一の方法も、同様に、
for the norm of theta to be
シータのノルムが大きくなる、という事だ。
large, but what
だが我らが行っている
we are doing in the optimization
最適化の目的関数は、
objective is we are
以下のような条件を満たした
trying to find a setting
シータの組を探すという事だった：
of parameters where the norm
その条件とはシータのノルムが
of theta is small, and so
小さくなる、という物、つまり、
you know, so this doesn't
これはパラメータベクトルのシータにとって
seem like such a good direction
良い方向では
for the parameter vector and theta.
無さそうだ。
In contrast, just look at a different decision boundary.
これと比較して、別の決定境界を見てみよう。
Here, let's say, this SVM chooses
今度は、このSVMはこんな決定境界を
that decision boundary.
選んだとしよう。
Now the is going to be very different.
こんどは随分と違う絵となる。
If that is the decision boundary,
これが決定境界だとすると、
here is the
それに対応したシータの方向は
corresponding direction for theta.
こうなる。
So, with the direction
さて、この決定境界、
boundary you know, that
垂直な直線に、
vertical line that corresponds
対応した決定境界は、
to it is possible to
線形代数を用いて
show using linear algebra that
証明する事が出来るのだが、
the way to get that green decision
この緑の決定境界を得る方法は、
boundary is have the vector of theta be
それと直角の
at 90 degrees to it,
シータベクトルを持てば良い。
and now if you look
そしてあなたのデータを
at the projection of your
ベクトルシータに
data onto the vector
射影した物を見ると、
x, lets say its before
前と同様にこの手本を
this example is my example of x1. So when
手本x(1)とすると、
I project this on to x,
これをシータに射影すると、
or onto theta, what I find is that this is P1.
これがp(1)となる。
That length there is P1.
この長さがp(1)。
The other example, that
別の手本、この手本にも
example is and I
同様の射影を
do the same projection and
行って、
what I find is that this
この長さ、
length here is a
ここが、p(2)となり、
P2 really that is going to be less than 0.
これは0未満となる。
And you notice that now
そして見て分かるように、
P1 and P2, these lengths
ここでのp(1)とp(2)、
of the projections are going to
これら射影の長さは、
be much bigger, and so
もっと大きくなっている。
if we still need to enforce
だから、この制約、
these constraints that P1 of
p(1) シータのノルム が
the norm of theta is phase
1以上、という制約が
number one because P1 is so much bigger now.
ここでも満たされている必要があるとすると、p(1)はいまやもっと大きくなったので
The normal can be smaller.
ノルムは小さくなれる。
And so, what this means is
すると、この意味する所は、
that by choosing the decision
決定境界を、
boundary shown on the right
左に示したような物では無く右側に示したような物を
instead of on the left, the
選ぶ事によって、
SVM can make the
SVMはパラメータシータのノルムを
norm of the parameters theta
もっと小さくする事が出来る。
much smaller. So, if we can
すると、シータのノルムを
make the norm of theta smaller and
小さくする事が出来ると、
therefore make the squared norm of
それはシータのノルムの二乗も
theta smaller, which is
小さくなるので、
why the SVM
それこそが、SVMが
would choose this hypothesis on the right instead.
右側の仮説の方を選ぶであろう理由となる。
And this is how
そしてこのようにして、
the SVM gives rise
SVMは大きなマージンの分類の効果を
to this large margin certification effect.
生み出す。
Mainly, if you look
例えば、この緑の直線を見ると、
at this green line, if you look at this green
この緑の仮説を見ると、
hypothesis we want the
我らは、陽性と陰性の手本の
projections of my positive
シータに対する射影を
and negative examples onto theta to be large, and
大きくしたい。
the only way for that to
これを真に保つ、唯一の方法は、
hold true this is if surrounding the green line.
緑の線を囲むとすると、
There's this large margin, there's
この大きなマージンが存在する事、
this large gap that separates
この陽性と陰性の手本を分離する時に
positive and negative examples is
大きなギャップが存在する事、
really the magnitude of this gap.
実際にこのギャップの大きさ、
The magnitude of this margin
このマージンの大きさは、
is exactly the values of
実際にp(1)、p(2)、p(3)などの
P1, P2, P3 and so on.
値である。
And so by making the margin
つまりこのマージンを大きくする事で、
large, by these tyros P1,
これらp(1)、p(2)、p(3)などを
P2, P3 and so on that's
大きくしようとする事で、
the SVM can end up with
SVMは結果として
a smaller value for the
シータのノルムを小さくする事が出来る、
norm of theta which is what it is trying to do in the objective.
そしてそれこそが目的関数でやろうとしていた事だった。
And this is why this
こんな訳で、サポートベクターマシンは
machine ends up with enlarge
分類器のマージンを
margin classifiers because itss
広げる事になる、何故なら、
trying to maximize the norm
それはp(1)のノルム、
of these P1 which is the distance from
それは決定境界から手本までの距離だが、
the training examples to the decision boundary.
それを最大化しようとするからだ。
Finally, we did this whole derivation
最後に、我らはこれらの導出を
using this simplification that the
全てパラメータのシータ0が、イコール0という
parameter theta 0 must be equal to 0.
単純化の元で行なってきた。
The effect of that as
その効果を簡単に
I mentioned briefly, is that if
伝えておく。
theta 0 is equal to
シータ0が0と等しい時というのは、
0 what that means
それの意味する所は、
is that we are entertaining decision
決定境界をいつも、
boundaries that pass through the
原点を通る物だけで
origins of decision boundaries pass through
決めるという事に対応する。
the origin like that, if you
こんな風に原点を通る。
allow theta zero to
もしシータ0に、0以外の値を
be non 0 then what
許すとすると、
that means is that you entertain the
その意味する所は、
decision boundaries that did not
原点を通らない決定境界も
cross through the origin, like that one I just drew.
試していくという事を意味する。今ここに描いたような物も、だ。
And I'm not going to do
これの完全な証明を
the full derivation that. It
する気は無いが、
turns out that this same
まさにそっくりの
large margin proof works in
大きなマージンの証明が
pretty much in exactly the same way.
ほとんど同様に成立する。
And there's a generalization of this
そして、ここまで長々と
argument that we just went through
やってきた議論を
them long ago through that shows
一般化出来て、
that even when theta
シータ0が非ゼロでも、
0 is non 0, what
SVMが試みるのはーー
the SVM is trying to do when you have this optimization objective.
この最適化の目的関数を持つ時に、
Which again corresponds to the
これもふたたび、Cがとても大きい場合に
case of when C is very large.
対応するが、
But it is possible to
ここでも、シータ0が0で無くても
show that, you know, when theta
このサポートベクターマシンは
is not equal to 0 this
同様に陽性と陰性の
support vector machine is still
手本を分離するような、
finding is really trying
大きなマージンの分離を
to find the large margin
探そうとする、という事を
separator that between the positive and negative
示す事が出来る。
examples. So that
以上が、サポートベクターマシンが
explains how this support vector machine is a large margin classifier.
どのように大きなマージンの分類器であるのか、の説明だ。
In the next video we
次のビデオでは、
will start to talk about how
これらのSVMの考え方の
to take some of these
幾つかを用いて、
SVM ideas and start to
それを複雑な
apply them to build a complex
非線型の分類器を構築する為に
nonlinear classifiers.
適用していく方法を見ていこう。